Tristan Laidlow

Robotics Researcher

I am a research fellow in the Dyson Robotics Lab with Prof. Andrew Davison at Imperial College London.

My current research interests are in developing algorithms that enable robots to understand and interact with their environment. To this end, my research focuses on dense 3D reconstruction with geometric priors, efficient scene segmentation using neural fields, and learning robust object manipulation policies.

CONTACT

E-mail t.laidlow15@imperial.ac.uk

Website tlaidlow.github.io

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/tristan-laidlow

Google Scholar scholar.google.com/citations?user=bmOi48IAAAAJ

EXPERIENCE

Dyson Robotics Lab Dyson Research Fellow

> Oct. 2019 – Present Imperial College London, UK

> > Supervisor.: ProfAndrew Davison

Lead research projects developing state-of-the-art vision algorithms for robotic applications.

Graduate Teaching Assistant

C333: Robotics

Jan. 2016 – Apr. 2021 Imperial College London, UK

Assisted students in implementing filter-based navigation algorithms for mobile robotics.

Research Assistant

Dynamic Systems Lab

University of Toronto Institute for Aerospace Studies, Canada Apr. 2013 - Aug. 2015

Established the foundations for a new aerial robotics research testbed and implemented a

stabilizing controller for an aerial robotic platform using vision-based localization.

Research Assistant

Technologies for Aging Gracefully Lab

Apr. 2012 – Aug. 2012 University of Toronto, Canada

Developed a user interface for the Accessible, Large-Print, Listening and Talking (ALLT) e-

Book Project for people with low vision or mobility impairments.

Strategic Information Analyst

Interior Health Authority Jan. 2009 - Aug. 2011

Kelowna, British Columbia, Canada

Developed solutions for smoothing the use of hospital resources, reducing surgical

cancellations, and lowering patient wait times by examining scheduling practices, analyzing

patient data, and creating simulation models.

EDUCATION

2015 - 2019 Doctor of Philosophy (Computer Science)

Imperial College London, UK

Thesis: Robust Multimodal Dense SLAM Supervisor: Dr. Stefan Leutenegger

2011 - 2015 Bachelor of Applied Science (Engineering Science)

Major: Aerospace Engineering, Minor: Robotics & Mechatronics

University of Toronto, Canada

Thesis: Real-Time Motion Generation for Aerial Vehicles in Response to Musical Signals

Supervisor: Prof. Angela Schoellig

Master of Science (Management Science) 2007 - 2008

Queen's University, Canada

Thesis: An Adaptive Algorithm for the Optimal Order Quantity in the Non-Stationary

Newsvendor Problem with Censored Demand

Supervisor: Prof. Jeffrey McGill

2002 - 2007**Bachelor of Science (Economics)**

University of Victoria, Canada

Thesis: Using a Discrete-Event Simulation to Examine Emergency Department Congestion

at Royal Inland Hospital

Supervisor: Prof. Joseph Schaafsma

SKILLS

Programming Python, C++, CUDA Deep Learning PyTorch, TensorFlow